Hi, this is the homepage of DaVinci Resolve.
You can see the projects you have already done here.
I am going to open a new project now.
When we open DaVinci Resolve,
Media page, Cut page, Edit page, Grading page, Fairlight
page, and finally they would have given you the Delivery page.
First, let's go to the Edit page.
Go to the Edit page and click Media.
If you right click here, you will see Import Media.
If you click on it, you can import any media you want.
Now, I am going to...
Umm...
I have kept the coarse footage here.
I am going to import all the footage I need.
Here, it will ask change the frame rate.
It is up to you whether you want to change the frame rate or not.
I am going to drag this footage in the timeline.
I don't need audio. I will cut the audio.
Now, the next step is to go to the grading page.
Once you go to the page, the layout will look like this.
Before grading a footage, we need to know
why it is being shot in Log.
Why is the camera being shot in Log instead of Standard?
When we shoot in Standard, we don't get to see the
highlights and shadows in detail.
When we shoot in Log, we get to see the highlights and
shadows in detail.
Now, I am going to show you an example.
Here, we have the footage shot in Standard and in Log.
Let's see the variations in this.
This is the footage shot in Standard.
In this, the highlights will be more in this area.
The shadows will be darker in this area.
Why is it like this?
The highlights are more in the background than in the subject.
The shadows are more in the background than in the subject.
That is why, when we shoot in Standard, the highlights will
be over highlighted.
The shadows will be over shadowed.
Similarly, when we shoot in Log, this is the footage shot in Log.
This is the log footage.
The details got collected in the highlights.
It is difficult to get the details from the footage shot in Standard.
Even if we reduce the highlights and grade it,
it will look like a mashup.
We can't get the details from it.
If we grade it from the footage shot in Log,
we can get the details from it.
In this, the highlights are not over highlighted.
The shadows are not over highlighted.
Now we know why we shoot in Standard and Log.
When we shoot in Standard, we don't get the details from it.
When we shoot in Log, we get the details from it.
This is the job of the camera.
Now, let's see how to grade the footage.
Let me explain the tools first.
These are the primary color wheels.
These are the basic tools for color grading.
These are Lift, Gamma, Gain and Offset.
These four have different variations.
I will use the grayscale to show you the variations.
Lift is for contrast.
Gamma is also for contrast.
Let me show you the difference of these both.
Now, when we increase the contrast in Lift,
look at the feather rate of the grayscale.
Look at how sharp it is.
I will increase the contrast in Gamma.
Look at the feather rate of this.
The job of Lift is to increase the contrast in the videos
in the darker places.
The job of Gamma is to increase the contrast level in the
videos by increasing the feather rate of Gamma.
If the contrast is too high, the video will look black.
So we can use both Gamma and Lift in a video.
Now, Gain.
The job of Gain is to increase the highlight where there is highlights in the videos.
Now, if I increase the gain,
As you can see, the highlighted area get over highlighted.
This is the work of gain.
Next, we can see Off-set.
The use of Off-set is
Not of highlight or contrast.
To manage the colour tone, we use off-set
I will show you when I create the video.
Now, you have seen how Primary wheels work.
Next, we are going to see how Log wheels work.
You have a option in Primary color wheels.
If you click, the log wheels will change.
When we reduce the shadows, the place with shadows will
change to a prime contrast.
When we increase the contrast in the lifts,
the look will be spread out.
When we increase the contrast in the shadows, the place
with contrast will remain the same.
The work of midtone is same like Gamma.
When we reduce the midtone, you can see a difference.
This will stop the contrast.
This will give a stop.
It will cut the variation between highlight and contrast.
Next, we will see the highlights.
There we have seen the highlight when we increase the gain.
We have done the same thing here, but we have made it sharper.
The offset is the same here.
We always use the offset when we fix the color tone.
Next, we are going to see HDR wheels.
You know what HDR wheels are.
High Dynamic Range.
HDR wheels are the wheels next to Primary wheels.
Here it is.
Now, I am adjusting the High Dynamic Range.
This will elevate in the gray scale.
High Dynamic Range will have dark, shadow, light and global.
Primary wheels are mandatory.
The functions of  are like Dark, Shadows, Light and Global
Lift, Gamma, Gain and Offset.
Now, I am adjusting the Dark.
When it elevates in the gray scale,
you can understand what is happening there.
When High Dynamic Range works, it does not disturb the
points where contrast and highlights intersect.
When I adjust here, the contrast is adjusted where there is more contrast.
When I do the same in the shadows, the contrast is adjusted.
It does not disturb the intersecting points.
When we do Primary and Log wheels,
it disturbs the intersecting points.
But when we do it in HDR, it does not.
Next, we are going to see the Graph.
The first option is
Curves Custom.
This is for...We can adjust the RGB with this.
Not only that, it is a major option to adjust the
highlights and contrast.
The benefit of the Graph is we can bring the contrast range equal to highlight.
You can see when I adjust the Graph.
I am adjusting the Graph.
The contrast side is highlighted.
But the intersecting point has more feather rate.
This is a big plus point in the Graph.
When we use the Graph to adjust the contrast, it is even
better to watch the video.
Not only can we adjust the contrast, we can also adjust the
highlights.
Now, we have a good clarity for contrast and highlights.
Why I said this is,
When we change the color from Log,
our first step is to  adjust the contrast and highlights.
Now, I am going to show you the other tools randomly.
In the next videos, we will see how to use the tools.
We have seen the Primary Log Wheels,
HDR, and this is RGB Mixer.
RGB Mixer is Red, Green, Blue.
RGB Mixer is a tool to control these three.
Then, Motion Effects.
Motion Effects are the grains in some of our videos.
Motion Effects is used to reduce the grains and to control it.
Then, Graph Page.
In the Graph Page, we have seen only one graph.
In the Graph Page, we have 7 tools.
7 tools are Hue vs Hue.
Hue vs Hue is to control the color in a video.
Red, Green, Blue, Orange, Pink
We use Hue to bring many variations of colors in the video.
Hue vs Saturation.
In a video, we use this hue to increase pointed saturation.
hue vs luminance
luminance is considered as highlight.
In a colour changing place, if we want to raise the highlight
or to lower the highlight
This graph is used.
Fifth, luminance vs Saturation.
luminance is to increasing or lowering the highlight in the saturation.
Sixth, Saturation vs Saturation.
Saturation is concentrated in R value that is Red Value.
After increasing Saturation, our video becomes more red
and it shows the over raised red in the video.
we use the graph to control that.
Finally, Saturation vs luminance.
Next tool, Color Slice.
Color Slice is used to separate the colors in a video.
For example, Yellow, Red, Blue and Green in a video.
Color Slice is used to separate these folur colors in a video.
Qualifier.
We use Qualifier to change the color of a subject.
For example, we can change the color of our skin tone or
the subject in the background.
Power Window.
We use Power Window to mask and change the color of a video.
It has 5 tools. Circle, Rectangle, Pen Tool.
We use Circle, Rectangle, Pen Tool to mask.
Tracking.
We use Tracking to track the face using the power window.
Next tool, Magic Masking.
Magic Masking is used to rotate and separate the subject.
Next tool, Blur.
Blur is used to control the sharpness and blur of a video.
If we decrease the blur, it becomes sharp and if we
increase it, it becomes blur.
Now we know the maximum tools in the color page.
I will tell you what Scopes are.
We call this Scopes.
Scopes are used to decide the value range of
Red, Green and Blue values in a video.
There are 5 types of Scopes.
Parade, Waveform, Vector Scope,
Histogram and CIE Chromaticity.
With these Scopes, we can calculate
RGB, Skin Tones and Highlights.
We have keyframes next to the Scopes.
In video editing, as we add keyframes to zoom in and zoom out.
Likewise we can add keyframes in colours to do ups and downs.
Color page introduction is over.
Let's see how to create a video from the next chapter.