Hi, in this chapter, I am going to show you how to do day
for night.
Day for night means, we have shot a footage in the day.
We have to shift it to night in post.
We will see how to do that.
I have already imported a footage here.
We will see how to do day for night in this footage.
I will cut only the necessary portion in this footage.
I will cut the last part too.
I will remove the first frame.
Now, we will go to the color page.
Before doing day for night, we can bring this footage to a
basic color.
I will cut it like that.
A serial note.
I will reduce the Lift.
This way, we can reduce the contrast in everything.
Because we are doing day for night, if there is too much
contrast, it won't be good for day for night.
I will add a second node.
I will reduce the gamma.
I will add a third node.
We can slightly raise the gain this time.
I will add a fourth node.
I will increase the saturation.
I will increase the saturation in both the nodes and reduce
it in the third node.
I have reduced it in the third node.
I will add the next node.
In this node, we can start day for night.
First, I will go to the graph.
To do day for night, the tool we use the most is the graph.
I will go to curve custom.
I will link all the colors in this first.
If you drag and drop this place in the graph, the video
will look dull.
I will add the next node again.
In this node, I will reduce the saturation to this green.
In night, the color of the leaves won't be clear.
So, I will reduce the saturation.
I will go to the graph.
I will select the hue and saturation.
I will pin the green.
I will pin it and reduce the saturation.
I will add another node.
In this node, I will reduce the temperature.
In night, if the blue tone is high, it will give a night
feel.
I have reduced the temperature.
I will add another node.
In this node, I will qualify the highlights and make it
white.
Because there is no chance of getting blue in highlights.
So, I will reduce the blue in highlights.
I will increase the blur radius.
I will reduce the saturation.
I will add a serial node again.
In this node, we can use gamma light.
I will add the next node.
In this node, I will add maskings.
First, I will add a mask to this node.
I will increase the feather rate.
I will invert this mask.
After inverting, I will reduce the gain to the surrounding
areas.
I have reduced the gain.
I will show you the difference.
I will add another node.
I will copy this node and paste it in this node.
After pasting, I will off invert in masking.
After that, I will reset the primary wheels.
Here, I will increase the gain slightly in the face.
I will add the next node.
In the 15th node, I will increase the blue in gamma.
I will add another node.
In this node, I will reduce the highlight fully.
In the 17th node, I will go to the RGB mixer and reduce the
blue tone.
I will add the next node.
In the 18th node, I will go to the masking and select the
gradient node.
I will face this side and darken the outside.
I will add the next node.
In this node, I will reduce the gamma slightly.
I will add another node.
In this node, I will reduce the temperature again.
In this node, I will qualify.
If I qualify here, It will select the background except the
subject's face .
I will turn off the highlight.
Now, I will reduce the gain fully.
After reducing the gain,
The highlighed in the face gets desolved.
I will add another node.
In the graph, I will link all the colors.
I will decrease the graph.
I will add another node.
In this node, I will go to the HDR wheels.
In the HDR wheels, I will adjust the global.
The reason why I adjust the global is,
In the primary wheels, we will use color tone for offset.
If we want to make it more detailed, we can use the HDR
wheels.
In the HDR wheels, we will use global.
In the global, I will raise the point towards blue.
You can see the difference when I raise the point.
You can adjust the point according to your needs.
I have adjusted the global point.
After adjusting, I will decrease the exposure option which
is down here.
You can see the video becomes darker when I decrease the
exposure.
I will also decrease the saturation.
I will add the next node.
In this node, I will go to maskings.
I will use the pen tool.
I will draw the highlight points.
Increase the softness after the rough draw
I will adjust the feather rate inside.
I will go to the primary wheels and decrease the gain.
I will turn it off and show you the difference between the
previous and the current one.
When you are tracking, you have to do it frame by frame.
If you give auto-track, it may collapse.
I will add the next node again.
In the 24th node, I am going to reduce the Highlight and
Saturation in the Primary Wheels.
First I will reduce the Highlight.
Then I will reduce the Saturation.
Don't reduce the Saturation too much, just reduce it
slightly.
The reason why I have reduced the Saturation in the video
is, the color of the night will always be considered as
grey.
In the night mode, the color of the night is grey, not blue.
So to give a grey feel, if we dissolve all the colors, we
will get a grey feel.
I will add next node again.
In this, I will go to Blur and reduce the Radius.
I have reduced it to 0.4.
I will add the next node.
In this node, I will reduce the Color Boost in the Primary
Wheels.
When we reduce the Color Boost, we have to slightly
decrease the color of the major color we have ruled in the
video.
Day for Night has been completed.
Let's see the difference.
I will keep it on full screen.
This is the log footage.
And this is Day for Night.
In this footage, Day for Night is not proper.
If we want Day for Night to be proper, we have to shoot in
pre-production.
If you shoot in the place where the Highlight is less, you
can shoot Day for Night easily.