In this chapter, I am going to tell you about the small
iconic points in Davinci Resolve.
Let's take a look at that.
I have already copied and pasted two footages.
I have a footage here and a footage here.
I am going to the color page.
I am going to disable the color of this video.
I am going to disable it and add only one node.
This footage is in the log and this footage is in the grid.
There is an option to short match this footage in the log.
Select this footage.
If you right click on this footage using the cursor, there
is an option called short match to this clip.
You just need to click it once.
The color in this footage will be applied to this footage.
If you are watching a movie and you like the color of that
movie, you can short match that color in a footage.
I will show you how to do that.
I have a footage in the movie.
If you want to apply the color in this footage, select this
footage.
If you right click on this footage and click on short match
to this clip, the color in this footage will be applied to
this footage.
How does this short match work?
If you shoot both the clips at the same exposure at the
same place, the short match will work.
If I shoot both the clips at the same exposure at the same
place, the colour will be completed applied.
Second, let's look at face refinement.
I have opened this footage.
I have already graded it.
I will add a new node.
Click on effects.
Type face refinement in the search box.
You will see an effect.
Drag it to that node.
Then a column will open with the effect.
If you type direct faces in frame, a box will be visible in
their face.
If you type forward tracking, the box will be visible in
After tracking, we can turn off the effects.
I will zoom in that footage.
In this footage, you can adjust the temperature, tint,
softness, brightness of your face.
In the face you have tracked, you can adjust the side
lighting, eye shadows, eyes, lips, teeth, blush, forehead,
cheeks, chin.
I will adjust it randomly.
There is an option called shine removal.
When I raise that option, the highlights in their face will
be dissolved.
We can increase that highlight.
I will reset it.
We can adjust the tint.
We can adjust the color boost.
We can adjust the midtone.
We can adjust the contrast.
We can even smoothen the skin.
You can see the difference when I adjust it,
note it in the face.
This area and this area will be smooth.
Can you see?
I will reset it.
If you open the teeth, you can adjust the brightness.
You can see the difference
you can adjust the teeth color.
Like this, you can adjust all the parts of the face
separately.
Third one, how to apply LUTs in the video?
It is simple.
In the left side corner, there is an option called LUTs.
Open the installed LUTs.
You just need to double tap the LUTs.
LUTs will be applied in this node.
Fourth one,
Lightbox.
If you work on a big project, there will be many clips in
it.
All the clips will be visible in the Lightbox.
When we add a node, we can even change the size of the
nodes.
There is an option called clip in the right side corner.
If you drag it, you can increase and decrease the size of
the nodes.
If you choose the hand mode while previewing the nodes, it
will be easy for you to drag.