In this chapter, I am going to tell you about color rules.
Color rules are always 60, 30, 10.
60% of color is dominant color, 30% of color is highlight
color, and 10% of color is for spices.
I already have a footage here.
I am going to enter the color page.
I am putting full screen.
In this video, only brown is dominant.
Color family may be there, but the palette should not
change.
Color family means, all similar colors are included in the
color family.
30% of color is in yellow.
Yellow is here, and yellow is here.
White and black do not come in the color palette.
White and black are always common.
So, we do not include them in the color palette.
In this, 60% of color is brown, 30% is yellow, and 10% is
red for spices.
When we shoot and grade, if we follow these color rules and
fix the pattern, the video will come out well.
What I just said are pattern rules.
There are many rules in color.
That is, emotions of color.
Each emotion has its own color.
I will finally display all of them to you.
Watch and learn.