Hi, what is the purpose of this course and how is it going
to be?
First thing, we are using damage resolve to color grade.
After all these years of experience in color grading, I
have come to know a lot of tricks and techniques.
I am going to teach you all of these in a short time of
period.
Just at 699, I will give you this complete color grading
course.
This is the world's cheapest color grading course.
Our course is not only available in Tamil, Hindi, English
and Telugu are available in 3 additional languages.
You will have lifetime access to this course.
Not only that, I will keep updating you with new videos
every 3 months.
Basic 2 Advanced Color Grading Classes will be available
for you.
Once you purchase the course, we will send 6 lakh footages
and 400 lakhs to your login mobile number or email.
You can use it and practice grading.
When you complete this course, you can also become a
professional color grader.