Chapter 2
In our last video, we saw the tools in the color page.
We will see how to grade a video using those tools in the
coming videos.
I have already imported a footage here.
In color grading, our first step is to add notes.
Why do we add notes?
Only when we color layer by layer, we can separate the
subject and background in the video and show it beautifully.
The most important thing in this is that we should never
color in the first note.
We always add a note and start grading from there.
If we want to delete a color, we can delete it.
In the first step, I am going to raise the contrast in the
grading.
In log footage, the shadows are always filled to make it
look flat.
So when we raise the contrast, the subject and background
will be elevated first.
I will now raise the contrast in the lift.
I have kept it at minus till now.
I will now add the second note again.
I will add the same serial note with the add note.
Next, I will reduce the gamma.
I will keep the gamma at minus.
Why do I adjust the lift and gamma?
In the previous video, I told you that when we adjust the
lift, it will be sharper.
When we adjust the gamma, the feather rate will increase.
When I adjust the lift in the first note and gamma in the
second note, the contrast in the video will be calibrated
correctly.
I have added the third note now.
I will reduce the lift again.
Why? I need more contrast because there are some shadows
around.
In grading, the second step is to increase the highlight,
that is, adjust the exposure.
I will use the gain to adjust the highlight.
Because gain is the tool to adjust the highlight.
I have adjusted the gain.
This exposure is enough for me.
If I want, I can add another note and raise it.
I have added the next note again.
In grading, the third step is saturation.
I have kept the saturation at full in one note.
I will add another note in another note.
I have kept the saturation at full in this note.
I will add the next note.
I will add another note again.
I will reduce the saturation in this note.
Why did I increase the saturation in two notes and reduce
the saturation in the third note?
I told you in the first class that saturation is always
boosted by red.
To control that red, I kept the saturation at full in two
notes.
When I reduce the saturation in the third note, the color
is easily calibrated.
I will add the next note.
In grading, the fourth step is WB, that is, white balance.
When we do white balance in a video, it is good to watch
that video.
I am adding a note.
I will decrease the temperature of this note.
Now I have decreased the temperature.
Let's see the difference between these two.
The video is looking yellow at first.
Now I will decrease the temperature and enable this note.
Now we have a similar tone in the video.
But this is the basic color grading.
Above this, there is tone fixing, masking, skin tone
calibrating, etc.
Now let's add the next note.
I added another note.
In this, the primary wheels would have given us an option
called contrast.
When I raise this, you will get a separation between the
background and foreground.
If you see now, I will disable it and show you.
Look at this.
Before adjusting the contrast, we would have had shadows in
the video.
Now if I increase the contrast, there will be a separation
between the subject and the background.
I will add the next note.
After adding the next note, I will go to log wheels.
I told you about log wheels.
Whichever place is darker should be over contrasted.
In this note, I will raise the shadows.
Now when you see, you will know the difference.
In the video, whichever place is darker, their hair, their
eyes, and the subjects in the background.
I will add the next note.
In this note, I am going to pick auto white balance.
If you take this qualifier and pick a place where their
face is yellow, the tone of the video will change
completely.
But using auto white balance is dangerous.
We can adjust it manually.
I will add the next note.
In this note, there is a tool called shadows.
I am going to minus this.
When I minus, what happens is, the place where the shadows
are already too much, will get decrease.
I will disable it and show you.
You will know this.
I have added the next note.
Now I am going to control the offset.
Offset is what I told you in the previous video.
It is used to change the tone of the video.
In a video, if we want a green tone, now usually what we do
is, we raise the green.
But in grading, we should not always raise the green.
For that, we have to decrease the opposite color.
When we do that, we will automatically rule the green value.
If you want a green tone, you have to decrease the red.
If you want a red tone, you have to decrease the green.
If you want a blue tone, you have to decrease both the red
and the green.
Now I am going to decrease the red value in that note.
When I decrease the red value, here you can see that the
green is majorly ruling.
So we have seen how to grade in a video.
But these are the basic colors.
Now let us see the difference between the log2 graded
footage we worked on.
This is the log footage.
And this is the basic graded.
That is all for the second chapter.
We will see further in the coming videos.