Chapter 3
In the previous video, we saw how to bring log footage to a
basic grade.
We can also see how to mask that graded footage using a
power window.
There are three types of masking.
Highlight masking, shadow masking and alpha output.
We can see all three of them now.
Now, I will add the first node and grade the base.
I have set the necessary contrast in the lift.
In the second node, I will adjust the gamma.
In the third node, I will increase the gain as we saw in
the previous video.
In the fourth node, I will decrease the saturation in the
third node by increasing it in the 1st 2 nodes.
In the fourth node, I will decrease the temperature and
white balance.
Now, we have a basic grade.
We have a basic grade from log footage.
In this video, we will see how to mask using a power window.
I have added the next node.
I will go inside the power window.
First, I will add the gradient window.
The way this window works is, the side of the arrow mark
faces.
I will show you an example.
I will place it from this side.
I will go back to the primary wheels and reduce it.
I will show you the difference after reducing the gain.
I will show you an example.
If we place the gradient power window from the opposite
side of the light, it will be more effective.
I will add the next node.
In this node, I will add the circle window.
I will place it near her face.
I will adjust it in her face.
If you drag the point in the four corners, you can adjust
it.
If you drag the red dot in the circle, the feather rate
will increase.
If not, you can increase it here as well.
I adjusted it in her face.
In this node, I will increase both the gain and shadow.
The reason why I am increasing the shadow in this node is,
when we reduce the shadow, it becomes dark.
When we increase the shadow, it becomes brighter in darker
places.
That is why I am increasing the shadow.
I will add the next node.
In this node, I will choose the circle window again.
But, I am going to mask this circle window completely.
I will increase the feather rate.
Importantly, there is an option called invert.
If you click on it, the mask will start to fill the outer
area with color.
I have inverted it.
In the primary wheels, I will reduce the gamma.
After reducing the gamma, I will add the next node.
I will go back to the power window.
In the power window, I will choose the pen tool.
In the pen tool, I will draw the rectangle-like shadows on
the cheeks.
After drawing it,
I will increase the feather rate.
There is an option called whether the feather rate should
come inside or outside.
If we want it outside, we can keep it outside.
If we want it inside, we can keep it inside.
I have kept it outside.
I will go back to the primary wheels.
I will reduce the gain.
I will add the next node again.
So far, we have used the masking tool in four nodes.
Let's disable it.
This is what happens when there is no masking in the video.
If we add masking in the video itself and control the
highlight and shadows, the video will change like this.
Next, we are going to look at tracking.
Now, we have done the masking.
We have to track everything.
So, let's go to the tracker.
There is a tracker next to the power window.
First, I will choose the node that qualifies the face.
I have kept the video in the last frame.
So, I will give it a backward tracking.
If you click backward tracking, it will be backward tracked.
You can see that the face is being tracked.
As the face is being tracked backward, I have to do forward
tracking again.
Why? To make the tracker sharp.
Now, when we play it, the power window will travel with it.
I am going to track the other two nodes as well.
Another important thing.
The frame in which you are applying the power window, we
have to start tracking from that frame.
Otherwise, the tracking will collapse.
Now, we have tracked all the power windows that we added.
Next, let's see how the alpha output is.
I am in the 14th node now.
Again, I will choose a circle window.
I will choose it and place it near the face.
I will make the feather value 0.
If you right click from the nodes timeline, there will be
an option called add alpha output.
If you click on that, the output will be added in the blue
color.
If you connect the alpha point in the node to the output,
you will get the alpha output separately.
When you play this, the portion where you masked will be
played.
You have to decide where you can apply this alpha output.
In the masking that we did, not only the gain and shadows,
we can also change the colors.
I am increasing the temperature for their face.
Now, the temperature will increase for their face.
With this, the power window tracking class is complete.
We will see further in the next chapter.