Skin Calibrating and Qualifying
Why do we use Qualifying?
We use Qualifier for all single color patterns
When we use Qualifier for all single color patterns
That pattern will be shown as Qualifier
Now let's see how
I have already imported a footage
I will add it personally
I will give a basic grade
I have fixed a basic color tone as usual
Now let's see how to use Qualifier
I will add a new node
In this, there is an option called Qualifier near the power
window
Go inside and select this pin
Select this pin
If you point at the skin tone
It will pick the skin tone
If you want to see it clearly
Highlight it
After Highlighting
It will show the patches in skin tone
To clear this
There is a plus Qualifier
Choose that
After choosing, remove the paches
Now I have qualified the face oh the subject
But there are patches
Let's see how to clear this
In that Qualifier tool
There is an option called Blur Radius
Keep it at 100
After keeping it at 100
There is an option called Pre-Filter
Raise it a little
What Pre-Filter does is
It will clear all the pointed patches
Blur Radius is used to soften the edges
I am going to use Gain and Shadows
To calibrate the portion I qualified
First, I will raise the Gain
Then, I will raise the Shadow
There is a yellow light in the subject face
To clear that
We can reduce the Temperature and Saturation
We can turn off the Highlight
After turning it off
Look at the before and after
How the skin tone is calibrated
Now, we can clear the pores and pimples in the subject's
skin
In Primary Wheels
There is an option called Mid Details
If you keep it at minus, it will become soft
If you keep it at plus, it will become sharp
Let's keep it at minus 35
After smoothening the skin
The details in the subject's face will blend
So we have to add sharpness to this
I will add a new node
Let's go to Blur
After going to blur,
If the Radius is 0.47
We have to add texture to where it is blended
I will show you closely
Look at the difference
Before adding the Radius
After adding the Radius
If you don't add the Radius, it will be smooth
If you add the Radius, the skin will have this texture
In this footage, we have selected the subject's face
Qualified it
And done the shin calibrating too
In this graded footage,
To identify if the Highlight and Colors are correct
Let's check the Scope
I will open the Waveform in Scopes
In Waveform, the Highlight should not go above 1023
And the Shadows should not come below 768
The attribution of waveform is
In a video, If the Highlight is more on this side
And the Shadow is on the other side
The Waveform will be similar to that.
In Waveform, the Highlight will be more on the left side
And the Shadows will be more on the right side
To check if the Saturation is correct
Let's use the Parade
The Parade should not go above 1023 and the Shadows should
not come below 768
In Parade, the Red, Green and Blue
Did not go above 1023 and the Shadows did not come below 768
In this footage, the Highlight and Colors are correct
The 4th Chapter is completed
In the upcoming Chapter, we will see further