In Chapter 5
we are going to see how to use Color Wrapper and Color
Graph.
Before that, let's grade this video as usual.
I'll adjust Lift, Gamma, and raise the Gain.
Then I'll increase Saturation in 2 nodes and decrease in 1
node.
Then I'll adjust White Balance.
Now I've got a basic grade.
After getting a basic color, we can go to Color Wrapper and
change the color.
We can also go to Graph and change it.
Now I'm in Color Graph.
In Graph, we can link RGB and work.
Or if you want Red, Green, or Blue separately, you can
enable that too.
I'll link it.
We can adjust Contrast in Graph.
You can adjust it if you need to.
I didn't adjust Contrast here.
I'll go to Hue Graph.
Now I'll pin this violet color.
After pinning this violet, I'll get 3 points here.
The black point in the center is our pinning color.
When I adjust this, the hue will also change.
I'll change that violet color to blue.
I've changed it.
I'll add the next note.
I'll pick this green.
I've got the pinning point again.
I'll adjust this.
When I adjust this pinning point, the green leaves in the
back will change to brown.
I'll add the next note again.
I'll pick this green.
I'll change the hue in this.
Now we've pinned all the green leaves in the back and
changed the color.
I'll add the next node.
Or I'll go to Saturation.
In Saturation, the color we pin and rise will rise.
Now I'll pin this green and rise it.
If you look at this display, the green will adjust.
I'll add the next note again.
In this node, I'm going to adjust Hue vs Luminance.
I'm pinning this green.
When I pin and raise the color in the back, the Luminance
in the hue will increase.
But I don't need it right now, so I'll do it for you.
You can see in the display, the Luminance in the hue will
increase.
I'll reset it.
Next graph, Luminance vs Saturation.
How this graph works is,
I'll increase the Saturation in Luminance.
I'll select Luminance.
If I rise the pinning point, the blue light in the
highlight will increase.
I'll zoom in.
As you can see, the blue light in the highlight has
increased.
Next graph, Saturation vs Saturation.
This graph prioritizes the red value.
I'll add the next node.
I'll pin her face.
If I pin and raise her face, the red value in her face will
increase.
I don't need this now.
I'll add the next note.
Saturation vs Luminance.
This graph is used to increase and decrease the Luminance
in Saturation.
I'll pin the blue color.
If I pin and rise the blue color, the Luminance in
Saturation will increase.
I'll reset it.
I'll add the next node.
Now I'll upgrade the video.
First I'll pick the qualifier.
Then I'll qualify your face.
I'll turn on the highlight.
I'll add Blur Radius.
I'll turn on the pre-filter.
Now I'll increase the Gain and Shadows in the node I
qualified.
I'll turn off the highlight again.
Now I'll reduce the mid-value in her face.
Now I'll add a fresh node and reduce the Blur Radius.
I'll keep it at 0.48.
Then I'll add another fresh node.
Now I'll mask this.
I'll select Gradient Masking.
I'll face this gradient power window on the right side.
I'll reduce the gamma in this.
Then I'll add the next node.
I'll choose another power window in the circle.
I'll track her face.
As I said earlier, I'll track forward and backward.
I'll increase the gamma in the power window I added.
Now let's see the difference in this video.
This is the log footage and this is the color graded
footage.
In this video, we can do the same thing we did in the graph
in Color Wrapper.
I'll tell you how to do that too.
There will be a Color Wrapper next to the Qualifier.
I'll go into that.
After selecting this, I'll get a qualifying pin when I
enter the display.
I can use that pin to choose any color I want.
I'll choose blue.
Once you pin blue, you will have the option to control Hue,
Saturation and Luminance.
I can control Hue, Saturation and Luminance in this.
I'll change the color in the Wrapper to sky blue.
I'll increase the Saturation.
And I'll increase the Luminance.
Now you can see the difference between the Graph and the
Wrapper.
There is a difference between the Graph and the Wrapper.
If you choose a color in the Graph and increase it, it will
increase sharply.
The only colour you have chosen.
When we choose a color in the Wrapper, we choose similar
colors and increase them.
Chapter 5 is now complete.
In the next chapter, I'll introduce new tools.