Chapter 6
Magic Masking and the Keyframes. Let's see how to do it.
I have already imported a footage. I will go to the other
page.
As usual, I will do the basic grade first.
I have done the basic grade in this video. Let's see how to
do the magic mask in this.
I will add a fresh node.
After adding it,
There is a tool called magic masking near the tracker.
Click on it.
Before drawing the magic masking, check if your video is in
the first frame.
I will change it to better here. I will draw a rough
diagram on the subject.
Every sketch we do one by one will be considered as a
single strokes.
I have drawn a rough diagram on the subject. Let's do
forward tracking on it.
After drawing, click on the forward tracking option. The
video will start tracking forward.
It will take some time, but the result will be better.
As soon as the magic masking is tracked, we can check the
highlight in the power window.
I will turn on the highlight now.
When I turn on the highlight, I can clearly see the edges
of the subject.
I will increase the radius now.
When I increase the radius, the feather rate will increase
in the subject.
The magic masking is used to separate the subject and to
animate the subject.
I will right click on the magic masking and connect it to
the alpha output.
I will go back to the edit page and duplicate this clip.
I have turned off the magic masking node in the first layer
of the video.
I have turned it on in the second layer only.
What we insert in between the first and second layers will
be reflected in the second layer.
I have the full video in the first layer and the alpha
output in the third layer.
Let's insert a text in the second layer.
I have inserted a basic text.
I will type Wencuts.
We have inserted the text behind the third layer of the
alpha output.
This text will be in the background of the subject.
Not only that, you can also lighten the subject that has
been magic masked.
I will increase the temperature now.
The temperature I have increased will be reflected in the
subject.
We don't have to do anything in the magic masking.
We just have to roughly draw the subject.
Next, let's look at the keyframes.
I will select the keyframe tool.
I will add a new node.
I am now in the 12th node.
The nodes are in the keyframes will shown as corrector.
I am now going to key the 12th corrector.
In this video, I will add a key to the 12th corrector in
the first frame.
I will add a key and increase the gain slightly.
The first key have been added.
I am going to add another key in the middle of this video
to reduce the gain.
Now, when I play the video, the range that I have set
before the video travels from here to here.
That is, from the first frame, until I set the next
keyframe, the colour will travel and be completed.
The reason why I use these keyframes is if you go from the
room to the outdoor, it will be dark in the indoor and
bright in the outdoor.
Before going from the indoor to the outdoor, this keyframe
is used for color changing.
There is another way to use this keyframe.
I will tell you that too.
First, I will go to the power window.
I will select a rectangle in the power window.
I will cover the rectangle so that the video is fully
spread.
In the rectangle power window that I selected,
I will set all the feathers to 0.
Go to soft,
Set here as 0.
Now all the edges will be dark.
In the first frame, I will add a keyframe like this.
In the middle of the video,
I will make sure that it is fully covered.
Now in the video,
I will raise the temperature in the first keyframe I set,
but I will not do anything in the middle of the keyframe.
The temperature that I set first will travel to the middle
of the frame through this power window.
Now let's see.
The window that I set first will travel to the middle of
the frame.
With this power window and keyframes, you can design your
video according to your sense.
Chapter 6 is completed with this.
In Chapter 7, let's see how to do low light grading.