Chapter 7.
Let's see how to grade both low light and without light
footage.
If you don't have a proper light footage, you will
definitely get grains.
Let's mash those grains and see how to grade them properly.
And let's see how the RGB mixer works.
You don't have to add much contrast in low light footage.
I'm adding a little bit of contrast.
Then I'm spreading the gamma a little bit.
I'm raising the gain in the 3rd node.
After raising the gain in the 3rd node, you can see a lot
of grains in that footage.
Grains.
I'm adding the 4th node.
We can grade the basic and then remove the grains.
I'm increasing the saturation.
Similarly, I'm reducing it in the 4th node.
I'm adjusting the white balance in the next node.
After white balance, I'm changing the dark blue tones in
the background.
I'm going to the color wrapper and picking this color.
I'm changing the hue.
This is greenish.
This is better for me.
I'm adding it in the next node.
Now.
Now I'm qualifying the face.
I'm picking the qualifier.
I'm changing the hue.
I'm qualifying the face.
After qualifying the face, I'm raising the gain in it.
The face got bright after editing.
I'm adding the next node.
In this node, there is a tool called motion effects next to
the RGB mixer.
If you raise the luma in this tool, all the grains will get
mash.
I'm zooming in the footage and increasing the luma.
When I increase the luma, all the grains will be removed.
But the face will get affected too
I'm adding the next node.
I'm setting the radius to 0.45.
If I didn't set the radius in this node, his face would be
blurred.
But because I set the radius, his eyes look sharp.
I'm adjusting the radius to 0.43.
Because we applied luma in this footage, we controlled all
these grains.
This is how much the grains are.
This is how much we controlled.
If there are grains in any footage you're grading, increase
the luma and control the radius.
Next, let's see how the RGB mixer works.
There is a RGB mixer tool next to the motion effects.
If you go into that tool, there are 3 color outputs.
Red, Green and Blue.
As I said in the beginning, to fix a color tone, you just
need to decrease the opposite color to the color tone you
choose.
The color tone you choose will start to rule.
I'm reducing the red output in the 12th node.
When I reduce the red output in the 12th node, the green
started to rule.
I've controlled the red in this node.
Because I controlled the red, the green flavor is slightly
added here.
I'll disable it and show you.
The first one was slightly red in the face and subject.
Now, because I reduced the red output, the green tone is
slightly increased.
Similarly, to fix a color tone, you just need to decrease
the opposite color to the color tone you choose.
The color tone you choose will start to rule.