Chapter 8
Special Effects and the Render Settings
When you create a video and render it, there are some
specific settings
In the settings, go to settings color management in the Da
Vanci
In the color management, go to Timeline Color Space and
Output Color Space
Both of these are in REC 709, so check them
And in the Da Vanci Resolve, go to Preferences
Choose Generals
Turn on Use Mac Display Color for Viewers
Use Mac Display Color will only show to Mac users
It won't show to Windows users
Special Effects
After creating a video, we can use these effects to add
glow, light rays and special effects
First, create a basic grade in the video
I'm in the 9th node now
There will be effects in the right side corner
Click on it, go to search and search for glow
Drag this glow and place it in the 9th node
After placing it, if you control it, the glow will rise in
the full video
To control it, go to the qualifier and qualify it where you
want
I'll turn on the highlight
I turned on the highlight and qualified it where I wanted
Now I'll drag the glow back and place it
Now when I raise the glow, the glow will rise in that place
I can also control the feather rate
Next, type light rays in the effects
Drag the light rays and place it in the 9th node
Wherever there is a highlight, the rays will form from there
It will be good when you try this in an outdoor footage
I'll add light rays in this footage
I'll drag the light rays and place it in the 11th node
It will form like this
I don't need it in all the places
I only need it in this place
I'll use masking and qualify it
We can even turn off the power window
I'll adjust it in this node
If you adjust the X and Y value, we can change the position
of the light rays
I'll increase the length of the light rays
I'll adjust the Y value
We can control the threshold of the light rays
We can even soften and sharpen the rays of the light rays
Now I'll turn off the light rays in this video
It will look like this when the light rays are turned on
If you use special effects like this in the video you are
grading, your video will be even better
Another important thing
You can even use the grab still for all the color scenes
you are grading
You can even use it for the next footage
If you right click on the footage you are grading, there is
an option called grab still
If you click on it, your let's save will appear in the
gallery
Then special effects
Let's see how to add a basic LED in special effects
Add a serial node
Drag the color space transform and add it to this
In the input color space, select the camera you took in this
I'll select Sony S-Gamut 3
Input gamma
We have to choose which log to shoot
This is Sony S-Log 3, I chose 3
In the output color space, we have to choose RED709
In the output gamma, we have to choose RED709A
You can bring a rush color video without controlling lift,
gamma, gain and offset
I'll show you the difference
Before and after
The reason why this basic LED is useful
If you apply this LED in the video before grading
It will be useful for you to get the saturation level equal
when you grade
Chapter 8 is completed with this
So far, we have covered the maximum tools in color page
After this, we have to learn how to grade using these tools
For that, I would have recorded the color grading in the
screen and put it in the voiceover
Check it out