Hi, so far we have seen about tools from chapter 1 to 8.
In the next class, we will see how to completely grade a
video.
The first thing I teach you about tools is that, before you
grade a video, you need to know how to use the tools.
Only then you will know which tools to use to adjust a
video.
I will show you how to grade a footage using the tools from
chapter 1 to 8.
I have already opened it.
I have already put the footages in individual folders.
Indoor Daylight and Indoor Nightlight. I have four folders
like this.
I will show you one by one.
Let's start with Outdoor Daylight.
I will drag this footage and put it here.
I will remove the audio.
In this clip, I will cut the necessary places.
Then I will cut it at the end.
I will go to the cover page.
As I said in the first class, the layout will be like this.
First, we will grade a basic.
I will right click and go to add node and add serial node.
I will reduce the lift here.
Then I will add the next node.
I will right click and go to add node and add serial.
In Mac, you can use the option edge.
In Windows, you can use the alt edge to add serial node.
I will reduce the gamma here.
I will add the next node.
I will increase the gain.
When I increase the gain, I will open the waveform.
It should not be more than 1023.
The reason why it should not be more than 1023 is that, the
left side of the video has too many highlights.
So, it's showing like that.
Let's keep it as it is.
I will add the next node.
Add serial node.
Now, I will bring the saturation in the video.
As I said in the first class, we can increase the
saturation in two nodes.
Let's reduce the saturation in the last node.
This is the basic grid in the video.
Now, I will increase the contrast.
Here it is.
I have increased the contrast.
When I increase the contrast, the subject and the
background will separate.
If It is faded, when I increase the contrast, the subject
and the background will separate.
I will add the next node.
I will reduce the saturation.
I will add the next node again.
You can add each node for each step.
Then, we will know which node is correct.
I will reduce the temperature.
I will add the next node again.
I am going to change this video to a rustic village color.
The rustic village color will be warm, dark and contrasty.
Let's change it to rustic village color.
I have not reduced the temperature in the first node.
I will increase the temperature in the next node.
I have increased the temperature to a warm tone.
I will add the next node again.
I will add the serial node.
I am going to qualify the face.
You can use color slice instead of qualifying.
As I said in the first video, we use color slice to select
the skin tones or to select the greens in the background.
How does this work?
I have the skin option here.
If I turn on the highlight, it will pick the skin tone.
This is optional.
If you don't want to use color slice, you can use qualify.
I am going to use qualify for now.
I am going to turn on the highlight.
I am going to qualify.
I am going to add the qualifier.
I will qualify the remaining.
I am going to increase the blur radius.
I am going to increase the pre-filter.
I am going to turn off the highlight.
I am going to increase the gain in this portion where I
qualified.
I have increased the gain.
After increasing the gain,
I am going to decrease the mid value.
This is to make the skin smoother.
I am going to add the next node.
The next step is to fix the color tone.
I told you about a rustic color.
After fixing the color tone, we can do masking or anything
else.
I am going to graph for tone fixing.
I am going to select the hue.
I am going to select the hue and pick the green.
I get this point tone.
If I drag this point, the color of the tree will change.
I will keep the tone as it is.
Since it is rustic,
I am going to make the leaves brownish.
I am going to add the next node.
What we are going to do now is we are going to add a
parallel node here.
What is a parallel node?
I am going to change the color tone throughout this video.
I am going to pick a leaf and change the color.
I am going to pick their skin tone and change the color.
I am going to pick their dress and change the color.
We have to do everything like an overlay.
I am going to add a parallel node.
I will add a new node.
When we add a parallel node, it will be a first layer,
second layer and third layer.
All three will be considered as one node.
But we can apply color layer by layer.
First, I have adjusted the leaf.
Second, I am going to adjust the skin tone.
While adjusting the skin tone, we can go to the vectorscope.
We can check the skin tone here.
There will be an indicator here.
If you don't see this indicator, you can go to the settings.
There is an option called show skin tone indicator.
If you turn it on, you will see an indicator here.
I will show you.
Do you see the skin tone indicator here?
Do you see the skin tone indicator?
There is a waveform here.
This waveform should be above the line.
Only then the skin tone will be correct.
You can adjust it slightly below or above.
That is not a problem.
This is because we all use cine lens.
We use Nikon, Sony,
Canon, Sigma, etc.
We use a variation of lens.
In one lens, the tint is on the green side.
In another lens, the tint is on the pink side.
If there is a variation in the lens, the skin tone will be
damaged.
That is not a problem.
You can adjust it by looking at the vectorscope.
In the 13th node,
I will go to hue vs saturation.
I will pick the skin tone here.
Can you see the dot, I will drag this out.
If you drag it, the color of the face will change.
I will keep this correctly.
I will drag it and reduce the redness.
The face will look red.
I will reduce the redness.
If you want, you can adjust it in the already qualified
node.
I will click on the 14th parallel node.
I will go to curves custom.
I will choose white.
I will adjust the luminance
I have adjusted it.
Now I will
Now I will right click on the parallel mixer, add node and
add it to the serial node.
Now I will add masking to this node.
First I will choose a circle.
I will increase the feather rate.
I will increase the gain in the mask.
I will turn it off.
You can see the difference between before and after.
I will add the next node again.
I will choose the same circle this time also.
I will make it so that the entire video is covered.
I will increase the feather rate.
I will invert this mask.
To make it feel like a vintage look.
I am going to primary wheels.
I'm adjusting gamma and gain
I'm turning it off to see the difference between before and
after giving vintage feel.
I'm adding next node again
I'm going back to masking
This time I'm using the pen tool
I'm using the pen tool
I told you in the first class
Light should be brighter on the side where the light travels
And darker on the side where there are more shadows
I'm going to form a triangle from the side where there are
more shadows
This is to show that the light travels from this side
I'm zooming in
I'm forming a triangle
You can see this triangle in most of the Hollywood movies
Their lighting will be like this
This is called a loop light
There will be light on one side of the face
And on the other side, there will be some fills
I'm increasing the feather rate of the triangle
I'm keeping it off
I will keep it on the outside
What I'm doing now
I'm increasing the gain of this triangle
This is to highlight the light that travels from this side
I'm turning it off to see the difference
Now you can see
You can see the difference between before and now
I'm adding the next node again
In this node
I'm going to add a gradient node
To the darker side
I've chosen the gradient node
I'm keeping the arrow mark on this side
I'm not placing it from the side
I'm placing it from a little above
As if it's crossed
Because the shadows are more in the head
So I'm turning it off
I'm reducing the gain
See the difference between before and now
I'm adding the next node again.
What I'm going to do in this node
I'm going to reduce the red in the frame
I told you to do it in offset to fix a color tone
But if you reduce a single color like this
You can do it in lift or gamma
I'm doing it in gamma
I'm decreasing the red
When you decrease it
You will see a good change
Between before and now
The red in the trees
And the red in the building
I dissolves all of this
Can you see the difference?
I'm adding the serial node again
I'm increasing the sharpness in this node
I'm going to the blur
I'm increasing the radius to 0.48
I've already told you why I'm increasing the sharpness
You can see the difference here
Look at the eyes properly
Note this area.
Now it's a blur
After adjusting it, it's a little sharper
I'm adding the next node again
What I'm going to do in this node
I'm going to increase the warmth
I'm increasing the temperature
It's a little bluish here
After increasing the temperature
The pattern is fixed
I'm adding the next node again
What I'm going to do in this node
In masking
I'm choosing a round
I'm going to darken this side
I'm pointing it here
I'm increasing the feather rate
Now I'm going to reduce the gain in the primary wheels
You can see the difference
I've already raised the gain in the triangle
I can raise it a little more
I can raise the gain a little more
I've added a pinch
I'm going back to the qualify node
I'm raising the gain a little more in her face
I've raised the gain
You can see the elevation on the subject and background
I'm adding the next node again
What I'm going to do in this node
I'm going to use qualify
I'm going to see if I can separate something in the
background
I'm going to pin this first
Turning on the lightning
It got pined in the highlighted place.
I'm increasing the blur radius
After increasing it,
I'm reducing the saturation here
I'm reducing the saturation in the highlights.
When I reduce it, it will match the rustic color
I'm turning off the highlight and disabling it
It will be a small difference
If we do it more precisely,
It will be a nice look when you see it fully
I'm adding the next node again
I'm going to qualify this highlight
I'm going to turning on the highlight
I'm qualifying this
I'm increasing the blur radius
I'm clicking the pre filter.
I'm turning off the highlight
I'm going to add glow in this node
I'm going to search for glow in the effects
I'm going to tract the glow
after that, I'm setting the shine threshold to 1000
I'm increasing the spread value
I'm showing before and after difference
Look at this
If there is a highlight, we got the highlighted details
SO our video is looking even better
I'm adding the next node again
I am turning off the effects
See the difference
In that node, we reduced the saturation in the building and
highlights In quantified image,
In qualified image, Gamma would be reduced
Gamma will separate the backgrounds from the main subject
You can see the difference
I will add a new node
I'm adding the serial node
I will calibrate the skin tone again
In skin tone, there are multiple colors like yellow, pink
and red
We have to correct all these
I will choose the qualifier again
I will turn on the highlight
I will qualify the face
I will choose the add qualifier again
I will increase the blur radius
In this node,
In the graph,
I am going to Hue Vs sat, by pinning this area
I am going to desaturation
If you look at it now, the pink and red is dissolved in the
face
First, it is more pink in this area
now it is dissolved now, I am adding the next node
In this node,
I am going to sat Vs sat
pick the skin tone
I am raising the pinned area
I will get a blush in the skin tone
What I am going to do is.
We did so many maskings
I am going to adjust the masking again
I am going to reduce the gamma in this masking
I am going to reduce the gamma in this node
I am going to reduce the gamma in this node too
Here too
Now everything fixed, I am going to add a new series node
In this node, I am going to use the color slice
Let me turn on the highlight first
I am going to pick the Blue
In this video, all the places I have picked are blue
We do not need major blue in rustic village color
So I am reducing the saturation
This is saturation and this is density
You can even change the hue of this
They have also given us an option to adjust the radius
When we adjust the this, the radius will also adjust
I will keep it in the center again
I have reduced the saturation
I have now turned off the highlight
If we look at the difference
Her hair has a little bit of blue
After adjusting it, the blue in her hair has disappeared
Colors like this are only used for this
If there is any color in the video that is in the height
We can use this to find it
I will add on the next node
I am going to qualify in this node again
I will turn on the highlight
I am going to qualify all these trees
I am going to choose the minus qualifier
I am minusing the highlighted character
I am going to turn off the highlight
After turning off the highlight
I am going to adjust the temperature of the primary wheels
I am going to raise the temperature
I am adjusting the temperature because
I want to get a warm feeling in the background
First it was a little bit blueish
Now after adjusting it, it has increased a little bit
In the node where we adjusted the glow
We can increase the saturation
We can use the saturation option here
We can also choose the color in the glow
If I keep it red
From the place where I qualified the glow
It will be a little bit red
So overall we have graded the video
In the vector scope also
We have the correct color in the radius
In the vector scope, if we have all the colors in the radius
It means that the color is proper in the video
Now we have graded the video
I will show the difference
This is the log footage
And this is the color graded
We should never over-contrast in a video
What will happen is
When we see it on a big screen
It will be imamatured
Now I am going to show you the tools
From chapter 1 to 8
I will use those tools and grade the video
Until you know how to use those tools
Go through those 8 chapters